<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title> - BonsaiDb Updates</title>
	<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Year of BonsaiDb: A retrospective and looking to the future</title>
		<published>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/one-year-anniversary/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/one-year-anniversary/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a new database aiming to be the most developer-friendly
Rust database. BonsaiDb has a unique feature set geared at solving many common
data problems. We have a page dedicated to answering the question: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;What is
BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today marks the one year anniversary of the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;commit&#x2F;43bd3a25b61fc7841c9554422d7bb46ad4362e59&quot;&gt;initial commit&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This project is largely a written by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ecton&quot;&gt;me (@Ecton)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
although I&#x27;m very thankful to have been accompanied along the way by
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;@daxpedda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. He is responsible for the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;fabruic&quot;&gt;QUIC networking
layer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, our currently removed OPAQUE-KE support, and above all,
countless long discussions and debates that not only led to starting this
project, but also to the easy-to-use API designs we have today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last few months, we&#x27;ve also had two additional contributors:
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;modprog&quot;&gt;@ModProg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;vbmade2000&quot;&gt;@vbmade2000&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I&#x27;m grateful for their
additions to the project, and I hope this year we see even more contributors as
BonsaiDb gains momentum.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Beginning%20a%20real%20bonsai%20cluster&quot; name=&quot;Beginning%20a%20real%20bonsai%20cluster&quot;&gt;
    Beginning a real bonsai cluster
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name BonsaiDb was suggested by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;@daxpedda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; after countless times
where we stumbled trying to pronounce the project&#x27;s former name: PliantDb. When
I &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;short-update-pliantdb-is-now-known-as-bonsaidb&#x2F;74&quot;&gt;announced the new name&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I researched trying to grow a bonsai
tree in the Las Vegas climate. My initial findings were that many of the iconic
types are difficult to grow here, and I ended up shelving the idea.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As March was approaching, I knew I wanted to commemorate the anniversary of the
first commit. I researched again and found two species that were great
candidates for being able to be grown mostly indoors. After some deliberation, I
decided to start with a Golden Gate (Tiger Bark) Ficus:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;&amp;#x2F;images&amp;#x2F;one-year-anniversary-ficus.jpg&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;One Year Anniversary Golden Gate Ficus&quot;  width=&quot;400&quot;  &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After giving the tree another week or two of adjustment to its new home, I&#x27;ll be
pruning it for the first time and attempting to grow a second tree from its
cuttings. Within the limits of being able to provide good living conditions for
each tree, I hope to expand the &amp;quot;cluster&amp;quot; each year and will share progress
pictures along the way!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#The%20first%20year%3A%20Inspiration&quot; name=&quot;The%20first%20year%3A%20Inspiration&quot;&gt;
    The first year: Inspiration
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inspiration for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; came from weeks and weeks of
discussions between &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ecton&quot;&gt;myself&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;@daxpedda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We were wanting
to build an cluster architecture for an MMO that:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was easy to deploy and maintain&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Was affodable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could scale horizontally&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could subdivide players by &amp;quot;location&amp;quot; within the cluster:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each location could have database&#x2F;cache&#x2F;cpu resources allocated dynamically&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each location would be Highly Available&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used as many Rust-written solutions as possible&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the start of our discussions, I was dead-set on using PostgreSQL and Redis
for our database&#x2F;caching needs. However both PostgreSQL and Redis aren&#x27;t easy to
deploy and maintain in a highly available cluster, and if I chose managed
solutions, they definitely weren&#x27;t affordable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When starting my last company, I chose &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;couchdb.apache.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;CouchDB&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for various reasons
that aren&#x27;t worth diving into. Through the ten years of growing that company, I
became intimately familiar with the simple yet powerful design of CouchDB.
Several times I pondered rewriting CouchDB atop PostgreSQL using JSONB columns
to see how it would perform. I never ended up taking any of those prototypes
very far, but the thought process helped me appreciate and understand CouchDB&#x27;s
inner workings better.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One day while working on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;cosmicverge&quot;&gt;Cosmic Verge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, it dawned on me: I had
built a small wrapper around &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sled.rs&quot;&gt;Sled&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that made it feel like a higher-level
database. What if I went further and built a CouchDB-like API atop Sled?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#The%20first%20year%3A%20Initial%20Goals&quot; name=&quot;The%20first%20year%3A%20Initial%20Goals&quot;&gt;
    The first year: Initial Goals
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I was hesitant to tell anyone I was building a database. Despite
relying on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sled.rs&quot;&gt;Sled&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for the low-level transactional storage, it still felt
like one of those projects that is usually ill-advised. I finally felt confident
enough in my reasoning of &lt;em&gt;why&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; I was building &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that I &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;did-i-say-i-was-refocusing&#x2F;58#pliantdb-the-core-of-cosmic-verge-2&quot;&gt;wrote a detailed
devlog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; describing the motivation for tackling this new
project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early on, I never had high ambitions for BonsaiDb. After all, this was the first
database I had ever written. The likelihood of me building a high-performance
database seemed low. Instead, I wanted to focus primarily on developer
experience, reliability, and ease of deployment. I tried to make intelligent
choices based on my expectations of what would be efficient, but I intentionally
avoided comparing BonsaiDb against other databases until &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;commerce-benchmark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;January of this
year&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me the selling points of BonsaiDb were (and still are):&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Straightforward to use and deploy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can write generic code that works regardless of how BonsaiDb is deployed.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;quot;Battery-powered&amp;quot; with common needs for developers, reducing complexity of deployments:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACID-compliant transactional document storage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lightweight Atomic Key-Value store (a-la Redis)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;PubSub&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unified and extensible authentication and permissions model&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Persistent Job Queue System (a la SQS&#x2F;Resque&#x2F;Sidekiq). Work on this has been
started but is not shipping yet, but it has been a goal from the start of
the project.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built in Rust, for Rust.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vision includes a &amp;quot;grows with you&amp;quot; pitch:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bi-directional replication&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quorum-based clustering&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modular plugin system to support &amp;quot;resuable&amp;quot; collections and services&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-3&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#BonsaiDb%20isn%27t%20just%20a%20toy&quot; name=&quot;BonsaiDb%20isn%27t%20just%20a%20toy&quot;&gt;
    BonsaiDb isn&amp;#x27;t just a toy
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In October a series of events made me look at porting the append-only B-Tree
implementation from CouchDB to Rust as a potential replacement for &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sled.rs&quot;&gt;Sled&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
in our architecture. In the end, the bug that I was experiencing on Mac &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-nebari-a-key-value-data-store-written-using-an-append-only-file-format&#x2F;81#what-caused-the-uncontrolled-memory-usage-5&quot;&gt;was
unrelated&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to Sled, but its symptoms manifested in such a way that
resembled issues others have had with Sled in the past.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After getting some basic unit tests working, I did something really stupid: I
benchmarked it against Sled and SQLite. Why was it stupid? It kicked off a
viscious few weeks, nearly reaffirming the common wisdom: why was I trying to
write my own database? I would stare &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;nebari-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;at microbenchmarks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
profiling results, tweak something, and try again. Over and over. For some
reason it just wasn&#x27;t occurring to me: the fact &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; was even in the
same realm as these highly optimized databases was exciting enough. Eventually,
I &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;introducing-nebari-a-key-value-data-store-written-using-an-append-only-file-format&#x2F;81#why-still-develop-nebari-6&quot;&gt;convinced myself&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; it was better for the future of BonsaiDb to
adopt Nebari.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January I was preparing to release our first alpha. I knew if I didn&#x27;t have
benchmarks available, it would be one of the first questions asked. I wrote a
benchmark suite aimed at comparing BonsaiDb against PostgreSQL in a simple
eCommerce setup. I wasn&#x27;t prepared for the results: BonsaiDb is significantly
faster than PostgreSQL &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;in this benchmark suite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month I set my focus &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;february-2022-update&#x2F;#Testing%20BonsaiDb%20with%20a%20large%20dataset&quot;&gt;testing large datasets&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and was able
to achieve performance again that exceeded my expectations. I no longer am
viewing BonsaiDb as an easy-to-use database that will be &amp;quot;good enough&amp;quot; for many
people. I now view BonsaiDb as having the potential to be a serious database
option for most people.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For being just one year old, I&#x27;m extremely happy with where BonsaiDb is today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-4&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Year%20Two%3A%20My%20Goals&quot; name=&quot;Year%20Two%3A%20My%20Goals&quot;&gt;
    Year Two: My Goals
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that surprised me was how much interest &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; garnered.
Despite not heavily advertising it, it&#x27;s accumulated a fair number of stars on
GitHub. It&#x27;s popular enough that I&#x27;ve been rethinking how I was planning on
implementing certain features. Outside of bug fixes and minor features, I
haven&#x27;t spent much time working on Nebari as it has been meeting BonsaiDb&#x27;s
needs. I would like to spend more time in this coming year making Nebari a
better crate for developers to consume directly. Ultimately, the more users
Nebari has, the more confidence everyone can have in BonsaiDb&#x27;s ACID compliance.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, there are several goals I have:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features, Features, Features&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: I&#x27;m excited at exploring a wide variety of
features aiming to make BonsaiDb more powerful and easier to use:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;pull&#x2F;220&quot;&gt;Ability to use BonsaiDb in non-async
code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;78&quot;&gt;Persistent Job Queue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;162&quot;&gt;Supporting Metrics&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;136&quot;&gt;Document Dependencies&#x2F;Foreign Keys&#x2F;Graph Relationships&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;69&quot;&gt;Collection Lifecycles&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;90&quot;&gt;Replication&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are countless other features I hope to explore as well, but those are
some of the higher priority items as I view them.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: I would like to be able to declare a stable version within the
next year. I&#x27;m currently treating BonsaiDb as if it&#x27;s stable: trying to
preserve backwards compatibility for the storage format, prioritizing bug
fixes, and keeping a thorough changelog.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By this time next year, I would like to be at a point where the core of
BonsaiDb is changing infrequently, and focus is on building higher level
abstractions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tooling&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A good, graphical database administration tool not only makes
exploring a database more approachable, it also can aide in quickly diagnosing
and fixing data issues. Because BonsaiDb is architected to not know about the
contents of the documents being stored, creating a good, generic
administration tool will be a fun challenge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Fostering an active developer community around BonsaiDb is
important for many reasons. As I mentioned before, the more users BonsaiDb
has, the more confident we can all feel about its reliability. Beyond that,
however, is something more fundamental for me: I thrive on success stories and
helping solve interesting data problems.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-5&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Help%20grow%20BonsaiDb&quot; name=&quot;Help%20grow%20BonsaiDb&quot;&gt;
    Help grow BonsaiDb
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building BonsaiDb has reawakened many of the passions I felt in my first
full-time computer-related job: working on REALbasic (now
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.xojo.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Xojo&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;). As I started getting schema design questions and
feature requests from potential users, I reflected on the joy those interactions
provided me. It is clear to me that one of the reasons I look back so fondly at
my first programming job is the wide array of problems I helped users solve.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the longest time, I held off on allowing any means of sponsoring development
of BonsaiDb. Until recently, I was still hoping to get back to writing an MMO
once BonsaiDb was mature enough. My dreams have changed in the past months: I
want to focus on bringing safe, high-level data-oriented application development
to Rust. Initially, that means getting BonsaiDb to a maturity level where it
meets my original vision.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many readers may not be aware that the early days of BonsaiDb development were
overlapped with my development of &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;gooey&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Gooey&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. To this day, it is the only
framework that meets my personal desires of application development. However,
it&#x27;s lacking many critical features&#x2F;widgets. I paused development because I want
to focus on BonsaiDb. Yet, I also want to begin writing GUI administration tools
for BonsaiDb soon.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to continue dedicating my focus to these areas of the Rust ecosystem:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BonsaiDb: Easy-to-use database that grows with you.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building cross-platform applications in Rust (with or without Gooey)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you would like to ensure my ability to continue working on these projects
full-time, I am now &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;sponsors&#x2F;ecton&quot;&gt;accepting sponsorship through GitHub
Sponsors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I have been working on open-source Rust projects since
November 2019 all funded by the sale of my previous startup. I would love the
opportunity to continue working on open-source full time without needing to
focus on building another startup. As I am not in dire need of finances, please
only sponsor me if you have truly disposable income.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important way to help grow BonsaiDb is to contribute. I&#x27;ve been working
on adding &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues?q=is%3Aissue+is%3Aopen+label%3A%22good+first+issue%22&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Good First Issue&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; tasks. If you&#x27;re looking to
contribute to an open-source Rust project, I would be honored to have you as
part of our team.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-6&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Trying%20out%20BonsaiDb&quot; name=&quot;Trying%20out%20BonsaiDb&quot;&gt;
    Trying out BonsaiDb
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic setup instructions and a list of
examples. We have started writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s
guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we have tried to write &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;good
documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would love to hear from you if you have questions or feedback. We have
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community Discourse forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&quot;&gt;Discord
server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also welcome anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;new&quot;&gt;open an
issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with any questions or
feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you build something with one of our libraries, we would love to hear
about it. Nothing makes us happier than hearing people are building things with
our crates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you to all of the wonderful people in the Khonsu Labs community and the
Rust ecosystem.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>BonsaiDb v0.3.0: Optimized views, bug fixes, and more</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/bonsaidb-v0-3-0/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/bonsaidb-v0-3-0/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a new database aiming to be the most developer-friendly
Rust database. BonsaiDb has a unique feature set geared at solving many common
data problems. We have a page dedicated to answering the question: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;What is
BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BonsaiDb &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.3.0&quot;&gt;v0.3.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has been released featuring optimized view
processing, bug fixes, and a few new features -- including one from a new
contributor!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optimization of the view processing system has been covered in the &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;february-2022-update#Optimizing%20View%20Mapping&quot;&gt;previous
blog post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Deleting%20users%20via%20StorageConnection&quot; name=&quot;Deleting%20users%20via%20StorageConnection&quot;&gt;
    Deleting users via StorageConnection
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new function, &lt;code&gt;delete_user()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; has been added to &lt;code&gt;StorageConnection&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, allowing
for users to not only be created but also deleted without direct database
access. This feature was added by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;vbmade2000&quot;&gt;@vbmade2000&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; -- now the third
contributor to the BonsaiDb repository!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BonsaiDb provides open-access its &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;latest&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;admin&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;admin schema types&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. This meant
that users could still be deleted, but it required doing so directly through
&lt;code&gt;Storage::admin()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, and couldn&#x27;t be done over a networked client, for example.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Querying%20Data%20by%20Prefix&quot; name=&quot;Querying%20Data%20by%20Prefix&quot;&gt;
    Querying Data by Prefix
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A user on Discord requested an easier way to be able to query data using a
prefix. For example, if the key type is a &lt;code&gt;String&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;, a query should
be able to be made for any matches that start with a given prefix. Collections
now support listing documents with a given prefix:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;derive&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Debug, Serialize, Deserialize, Default, Collection)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;collection&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(name = &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;MyCollection&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, primary_key = String)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;pub struct &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;MyCollection;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; results = MyCollection::list_with_prefix(String::from(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;), db).await?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;results&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; will contain all documents whose id&#x27;s start with &lt;code&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. The same
capability is also available for views:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;derive&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(View, Debug, Clone)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;view&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(name = &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;by-name&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, key = String, collection = MyCollection)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;struct &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;ByName;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; mapping in db
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .view::&amp;lt;ByName&amp;gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;with_key_prefix&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(String::from(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;))
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;query&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .await?
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    assert!(mapping.key.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;starts_with&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;a&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;));
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    println!(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt; in document &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{:?}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, mapping.key, mapping.source);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This functionality is powered by a new trait,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;docs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;key&#x2F;trait.IntoPrefixRange.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;IntoPrefixRange&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
which allows any custom key type to provide this functionality if possible.
BonsaiDb currently only provides implementations for &lt;code&gt;String&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; and the &lt;code&gt;Vec&amp;lt;u8&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
types.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Nebari%20Bug%20Fixes&quot; name=&quot;Nebari%20Bug%20Fixes&quot;&gt;
    Nebari Bug Fixes
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This release updates &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.4.0&quot;&gt;v0.4.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It contains
an important fix to ensure the transaction log is always written sequentially.
This edge case was discovered while running unit tests &amp;quot;one more time&amp;quot; before
preparing a release. A unit test that never failed suddenly failed. Here&#x27;s the
code in question that failed:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let mut&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; handles = Vec::new();
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;_ in &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;0&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;..&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;10 &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; manager = manager.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;clone&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;();
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    handles.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;push&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(std::thread::spawn(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;move &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;|| {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; id in &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;0_&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u32&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;..&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;1_000 &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;{
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; tx = manager.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;new_transaction&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;([&amp;amp;id.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;to_be_bytes&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()[..]]);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            tx.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;commit&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;().&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;unwrap&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;();
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }));
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The test then proceeds to wait for all the threads to finish and verify the
results. One thing it does is attempt to load each transaction one by one. At
first glance, this seems innocuous, but due to how Nebari is designed,
&lt;code&gt;new_transaction()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; allocates a transaction id, but it isn&#x27;t written to the
transaction log until &lt;code&gt;commit()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; occurs. I was &lt;em&gt;lucky&lt;&#x2F;em&gt; to have this test fail,
as it was a legitimate edge case that I hadn&#x27;t tested against. Needless to say,
there&#x27;s now a dedicated unit test to out-of-order writing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While working on this fix, however, I now have enough of a reason to implement
the next version of the transaction log to address a few design issues I&#x27;ve
thought of since writing it originally. The good news is that even if the
transaction log your database has currently is out of order, I plan to have the
upgrade process to the new format fix any ordering issues.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-3&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Getting%20Started&quot; name=&quot;Getting%20Started&quot;&gt;
    Getting Started
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic setup instructions and a list of
examples. We have started writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s
guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we have tried to write &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;good
documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear from you if you have questions or feedback. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community Discourse forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also welcome anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;new&quot;&gt;open an issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with any questions or feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dream big with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we believe that it can simplify writing and deploying complex, data-driven applications in Rust. We would love &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;labels&#x2F;good%20first%20issue&quot;&gt;additional contributors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who have similar passions and ambitions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you build something with one of our libraries, we would love to hear about it. Nothing makes us happier than hearing people are building things with our crates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>BonsaiDb February update: Supporting and Optimizing BonsaiDb</title>
		<published>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/february-2022-update/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/february-2022-update/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a new database aiming to be the most developer-friendly
Rust database. BonsaiDb has a unique feature set geared at solving many common
data problems. We have a page dedicated to answering the question: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;What is
BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s the last weekend of the month, and I want to make it a habit at the end of
each month to reflect on the previous month as well as talk about what I&#x27;m
currently focused on or what is coming next.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Status%20of%20the%20Alpha&quot; name=&quot;Status%20of%20the%20Alpha&quot;&gt;
    Status of the Alpha
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I released our initial alpha on February 5. I am ecstatic with the warm
reception. &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Our Discord server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has grown with several active users who
have been running BonsaiDb through its paces. Several bugs have been discovered
and fixed, with these releases happening in February:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.0&quot;&gt;v0.1.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Initial alpha release.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.1&quot;&gt;v0.1.1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;february-2022-update#Derive%20Macros&quot;&gt;Derive macros&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for common traits, many documentation
improvements, and memory-only databases for testing purposes.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.2&quot;&gt;v0.1.2&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Worked
around an undocumented panic within tokio::sleep on Windows that a user
experienced. Upstream patch merged as well.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.2.0&quot;&gt;v0.2.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;.&#x2F;bonsaidb-v0-2-0#Custom%20Primary%20Keys&quot;&gt;Custom
primary keys&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;bonsaidb-v0-2-0#LZ4%20Compression&quot;&gt;LZ4
compression&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and other minor improvements.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to these releases, the underlying storage layer (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;)
has been updated as well with several new features, bug fixes, and performance
improvements. The primary performance improvements that have been released have
centered around better usage of Rust&#x27;s type system to avoid extra allocations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Derive%20Macros&quot; name=&quot;Derive%20Macros&quot;&gt;
    Derive Macros
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ModProg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@ModProg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; noticed that I had open issues for adding derive macros for
some common traits. He became the second contributor to the BonsaiDb repository
when these macros were added in &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.1&quot;&gt;v0.1.1&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have an important design philosophy with BonsaiDb: Everything should be as
ergonomic as possible without macros. Macros should be used to improve an
already-well-designed API. I was comfortable writing
schemas by hand, but I recognized how often I copy and pasted boilerplate code
and then tweaked small portions -- a good sign that a macro would help!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way these macros are written is using a new crate &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ModProg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@ModProg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; wrote:
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ModProg&#x2F;attribute-derive&quot;&gt;attribute-derive&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. I&#x27;ve made a few
updates to the macros since his pull request, and it&#x27;s been a wonderful
experience. If you are looking into writing an attribute proc macro, you might
want to consider using this crate to make simplify parsing and support more
Rust-y syntaxes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Supporting%20BonsaiDb&quot; name=&quot;Supporting%20BonsaiDb&quot;&gt;
    Supporting BonsaiDb
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve tried to be very responsive to all questions, feedback, and issues. It&#x27;s
fun seeing BonsaiDb evaluated in new ways. As I recalled in &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;bonsaidb-v0-2-0#LZ4%20Compression&quot;&gt;the LZ4 Compression
feature introduction&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, I introduced that feature the day after a
potential user ran into space issues when evaluating BonsaiDb against their
current Sled code.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ModProg&#x2F;&quot;&gt;@ModProg&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; one morning tried running BonsaiDb on a Raspberry Pi, which
led to us diagnosing &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;GuillaumeGomez&#x2F;sysinfo&#x2F;issues&#x2F;700&quot;&gt;a bug&#x2F;edge case that&#x27;s been fixed in the &lt;code&gt;sysinfo&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;
crate&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It was a fun
morning debugging BonsaiDb, an async codebase, over a Discord screenshare
showing an ssh session into the Raspberry Pi running GDB!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, the same user that was testing a somewhat large dataset reported
an issue. It turned out to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&#x2F;commit&#x2F;125234cb3928ad4cd0c087d1afdd1d25ecd5710e&quot;&gt;a long-standing
bug&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
in Nebari&#x27;s transaction log reading code. The unit tests were inadequate, and
the only reason it was noticed was due to the LZ4 decompression failing once a
transaction log entry was large enough to be stored compressed across multiple
pages. The associated data isn&#x27;t currently being used outside of the
&lt;code&gt;list_executed_transactions()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; function, but eventually is planned to be a core
part of replication. A &lt;code&gt;cargo update&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; is all that is needed for BonsaiDb to
adopt the updated version of Nebari.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-3&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Testing%20BonsaiDb%20with%20a%20large%20dataset&quot; name=&quot;Testing%20BonsaiDb%20with%20a%20large%20dataset&quot;&gt;
    Testing BonsaiDb with a large dataset
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the bug that was just found, I still felt fairly confident in BonsaiDb&#x27;s
stability. Yet, it showed I hadn&#x27;t really tested a big dataset. With a user
trying to use BonsaiDb with a large dataset, I felt like I should do my own
testing to feel as confident in BonsaiDb&#x27;s abilities as I can be.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After looking through a few locations, I stumbled upon the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;openlibrary.org&#x2F;developers&#x2F;dumps&quot;&gt;Open Library Data
Dumps&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The data set I&#x27;m going to talk
about in this post contains these entities:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Collection&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Records&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Authors&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;9,145,605&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Editions&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;33,102,390&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Works&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;24,010,896&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The uncompressed file that this data is loaded from is 51,447mb. It contains
additional data from the types listed, so direct size comparisons aren&#x27;t able to
be done post-import.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing an importer was a fun project. Since the data being imported is too
large to read into RAM before processing, I started with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;5216db14f621233c0a5f7f8ba2ac62c7508b3bd5&#x2F;examples&#x2F;open-library&#x2F;examples&#x2F;open-library.rs#L440-L481&quot;&gt;a streaming TSV
parser&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
that uses &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;zesterer&#x2F;flume&quot;&gt;flume&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to send parsed records to another task. This uses a
bounded channel which will park the TSV parser thread if it outpaces the code
that saves the records to the disk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data importing logic is fairly straightforward. I have one method that
receives records from the TSV parser and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;5216db14f621233c0a5f7f8ba2ac62c7508b3bd5&#x2F;examples&#x2F;open-library&#x2F;examples&#x2F;open-library.rs#L545-L565&quot;&gt;creates batched
transactions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Importing the data with LZ4 compression enabled took 60m56s, and with
compression disabled it took 64m12s. The resulting file sizes are interesting:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Collection&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;LZ4 Uncompacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;LZ4 Compacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Uncompacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Compacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Authors&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;13,316mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,675mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;23,508mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;4,159mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Editions&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;74,459mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;33,155mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;118,330mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;38,372mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Works&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;40,443mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12,082mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;71,601mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;13,565mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BonsaiDb uses &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which uses an append-only file format for its
database. As the internal trees are built, old nodes are left behind on disk.
The only way to reclaim the disk space currently is to compact the database -- a
process which rewrites all the active data to a fresh file and swaps the files
atomically once fully synchronized. Compacting the compressed database took
6m55s, and compacting the uncompressed database took 7m20s.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After testing importing and overwriting the database several times, my
confidence level in BonsaiDb grew. I built a simple CLI that allows querying
authors, editions, and works by their unique ID. Everything was working great.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-4&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Querying%20large%20datasets%20with%20views&quot; name=&quot;Querying%20large%20datasets%20with%20views&quot;&gt;
    Querying large datasets with views
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to add support to show all the books (works) that an author wrote.
In the data coming from OpenLibrary, the &lt;code&gt;Work&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; type has a list of author roles.
This is the
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;view.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;View&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
definition that enables this query:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;derive&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(View, Debug, Clone)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;view&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(name = &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;by-author&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, collection = Work, key = String, value = u32)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;struct &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;WorksByAuthor;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;impl &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;CollectionViewSchema &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;WorksByAuthor {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;View = &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;map&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;document&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: CollectionDocument&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self::&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;View as View&amp;gt;::Collection&amp;gt;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    ) -&amp;gt; ViewMapResult&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self::&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;View&amp;gt; {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        document
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .contents
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .authors
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;into_iter&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;filter_map&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(|&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;role&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;| role.author)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;map&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(|&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;author&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;| {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;                document
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;                    .header
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;                    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;emit_key_and_value&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(author.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;into_key&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;().&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;replace&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;a&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;authors&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;), &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            })
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;collect&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data has some sanitization issues, including that keys sometimes are
shortened from &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;authors&#x2F;UNIQUEID&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;&#x2F;a&#x2F;UNIQUEID&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. Because importing the data
takes so long, I chose to clean up the data post-import rather than force myself
to re-run the import with some code to clean it up while importing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire function to display an author in the CLI is:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;async &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;summarize&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;database&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: &amp;amp;Database) -&amp;gt; anyhow::Result&amp;lt;()&amp;gt; {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;if let &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some(name) = &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.name {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        println!(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;Name: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, name);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;if let &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some(bio) = &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.bio {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        println!(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;Biography:&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;\n&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, bio.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;())
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; works = database
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .view::&amp;lt;WorksByAuthor&amp;gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;with_key&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.key.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;clone&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;())
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;query_with_collection_docs&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .await?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;if &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;!works.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;is_empty&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        println!(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;Works:&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; work in works.documents.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;values&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;if let &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Some(title) = &amp;amp;work.contents.title {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;                println!(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, work.contents.key, title)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    Ok(())
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this was easy to implement, I knew that this was going to be a painful
process to run. BonsaiDb&#x27;s views are lazily evaluated (with the exception of
unique views). The first time the view is accessed, the view will need to have
it&#x27;s &lt;code&gt;map()&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; function invoked for each document stored in the collection. For
the Works collection, that means processing 24 million rows.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial query took over an hour. Subsequent queries are fast: the &lt;code&gt;time open-library author OL1394865A&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; command completes in less than 400ms once the
view is indexed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really wanted to be able to turn this example into a benchmarking suite, and
the only way to do that without driving myself crazy was to start optimizing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-5&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Optimizing%20View%20Mapping&quot; name=&quot;Optimizing%20View%20Mapping&quot;&gt;
    Optimizing View Mapping
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial implementation of the view mapper was aimed at being correct, not
necessarily fast. It was originally designed to operate within
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sled.rs&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Sled&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which allowed non-transactional reads and writes. The
thought was that I could simply parallelize some loops and magically the view
mapping system would be faster because Sled would handle ensuring the data was
written to disk correctly with multi-threaded writes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After switching to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the view mapper always runs in a
transactional context. Each view mapping operation created its own transaction
-- the slowest way to write to the database. The biggest priority was going to
be to refactor the view mapper to batch the operations into larger transactions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;pull&#x2F;213&#x2F;commits&#x2F;b40607f753f1ab1808eb25a559e39fa0f6080541&quot;&gt;initial refactoring did just
that&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
and lowered the execution time significantly (~70%), but it also introduced a subtle
bug. As a result, not all mappings were being saved, but I
didn&#x27;t notice the issue until much later in the refactoring process.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One issue I was running into is that Nebari&#x27;s &lt;code&gt;TransactionTree&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; required an
exclusive borrow on the &lt;code&gt;ExecutingTransaction&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. This prevented being able to read
documents in one thread while writing view entries in another thread. I
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&#x2F;commit&#x2F;c195be84412b532dd1802379676cada106f6c62f&quot;&gt;refactored Nebari&#x27;s transaction handling
code&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
to allow this sort of parallelization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;pull&#x2F;213&#x2F;commits&#x2F;5216db14f621233c0a5f7f8ba2ac62c7508b3bd5&quot;&gt;adopting the new
functionality&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;,
here are the view mapping times on the compressed dataset:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;table&gt;&lt;thead&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;th&gt;Collection&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Size&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;View&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Unoptimized (LZ4)&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Optimized (LZ4)&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Optimized&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Uncompacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;th&gt;Compacted&lt;&#x2F;th&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;&lt;&#x2F;thead&gt;&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Works&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12,082mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;WorksByAuthor&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1h02m03s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;10m16s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;10m13s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;16,241mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;1,863mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Editions&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;33,155mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;EditionsByWork&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;26m52s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12m23s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;12m48s&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;17,507mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;td&gt;3,396mb&lt;&#x2F;td&gt;&lt;&#x2F;tr&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;tbody&gt;&lt;&#x2F;table&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While preparing this post, I&#x27;ve re-run the pre-optimized code and optimized code
to verify my notes on timings. When initially starting work on optimization, I
hadn&#x27;t implemented &lt;code&gt;EditionsByWork&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;. I&#x27;ve verified the output of both
unoptimized versions and optimized versions match a random set of entries that
I&#x27;ve compared against their website. To clarify some of the numbers: all sizes
listed above are the compressed sizes. Adding all sizes made the table too large
to be easily understood.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this stage, I no longer have any low hanging fruit from an algorithm
perspective. The next step in optimization would be to start profiling, but I&#x27;ve
reached my initial goals, so I&#x27;m going to be focusing on wrapping up this &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;pull&#x2F;213&quot;&gt;pull
request&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by finishing this
example. I would enjoy turning this into a benchmark suite, but I&#x27;m also not
excited at the prospects of how long such a suite would take to debug fully.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-6&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Next%20steps%20for%20BonsaiDb&quot; name=&quot;Next%20steps%20for%20BonsaiDb&quot;&gt;
    Next steps for BonsaiDb
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m going to continue prioritizing any stability or performance issues as they
are reported. There have been a few repeated requests that I&#x27;m going to be
working on soon: &amp;quot;best practices&amp;quot; overview, internal archicture documentation,
and a high-level roadmap.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several people have expressed interest in learning more about BonsaiDb&#x27;s
internals and roadmap with a goal of potentially contributing. I will be working
on those requests soon. In the meantime, I want to extend my offer to anyone
reading this: if you have any questions about any part of BonsaiDb, don&#x27;t
hesitate to ask! Regardless of your experience with Rust, if you&#x27;re excited at
the idea of helping build BonsaiDb, I will be happy to help you get up to speed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from improved documentation and project planning, I was working on
building a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;pull&#x2F;211&quot;&gt;persistent job
queue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which I will be
returning to and hopefully ship in March. I&#x27;m building this feature as a
standalone crate that will allow users to create independent job queues with
different job distribution strategies, and the long-term goal is for this crate
to be the first &amp;quot;plugin&amp;quot; for BonsaiDb.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-7&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Getting%20Started&quot; name=&quot;Getting%20Started&quot;&gt;
    Getting Started
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic setup instructions and a list of
examples. We have started writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s
guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we have tried to write &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;good
documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear from you if you have questions or feedback. We have
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community Discourse forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&quot;&gt;Discord
server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also welcome anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;new&quot;&gt;open an
issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with any questions or
feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dream big with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we believe that it can simplify
writing and deploying complex, data-driven applications in Rust. We would love
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;labels&#x2F;good%20first%20issue&quot;&gt;additional
contributors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
who have similar passions and ambitions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you build something with one of our libraries, we would love to hear
about it. Nothing makes us happier than hearing people are building things with
our crates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>BonsaiDb v0.2.0: Custom Primary Keys, LZ4 Compression</title>
		<published>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/bonsaidb-v0-2-0/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/bonsaidb-v0-2-0/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a new database aiming to be the most developer-friendly
Rust database. BonsaiDb has a unique feature set geared at solving many common
data problems. We have a page dedicated to answering the question: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;What is
BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m excited to announce &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.2.0&quot;&gt;v0.2.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which brings two major features in
addition to many small improvements and fixes. There are API-level changes that
are potentially breaking changes. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;tree&#x2F;main&#x2F;CHANGELOG.md&quot;&gt;CHANGELOG&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; should help navigate through the changes
necessary to update your projects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Custom%20Primary%20Keys&quot; name=&quot;Custom%20Primary%20Keys&quot;&gt;
    Custom Primary Keys
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One design decision that was made early in BonsaiDb&#x27;s development was to use a
u64 as the unique id&#x2F;primary key for all documents. This was largely done to
simplify the API, and I felt like it was reasonable that users could create an
alternate key using a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;latest&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;schema&#x2F;trait.ViewSchema.html#method.unique&quot;&gt;unique view&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve attempted twice before to change it to allow customizing the primary key,
but each time I ended up reverting the changes as I didn&#x27;t like the impact to
the API. However, this time I&#x27;ve succeeded in adding this API with minimal
impact to the high-level API.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;examples&#x2F;basic-local&#x2F;examples&#x2F;primary-keys.rs&quot;&gt;new example&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; demonstrates how this feature can be
used with the &lt;code&gt;Collection&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; derive macro:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;derive&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Debug, Serialize, Deserialize, Collection, Eq, PartialEq)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;collection&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(name = &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;multi-key&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;, primary_key = (u32, u64))]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;struct &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;MultiKey {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: String,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;async &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;test&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;C: Connection&amp;gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;db&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: C) -&amp;gt; anyhow::Result&amp;lt;()&amp;gt; {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; inserted = MultiKey {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        value: String::from(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;hello&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;),
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;insert_into&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;((&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;42&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;), &amp;amp;db)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .await?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; retrieved = MultiKey::get((&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;42&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;), &amp;amp;db)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .await?
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;expect&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;document not found&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The way this is implemented, any type that implements &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;latest&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;key&#x2F;trait.Key.html&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;Key&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; trait&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
isn&#x27;t too large can be used as a primary key. The current size limitation is
purely for optimization, and may be relaxed in the future.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about this feature can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;collection.html#primary-keys&quot;&gt;in our user guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#LZ4%20Compression&quot; name=&quot;LZ4%20Compression&quot;&gt;
    LZ4 Compression
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A potential user was originally trying to diagnose why BonsaiDb was creating
larger databases than Sled. After some troubleshooting, it was discovered that
they had enabled the &lt;code&gt;zstd&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; feature in Sled, enabling automatic compression of
data being stored.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a feature I had already planned on supporting, although my research had
led me to believe that LZ4 was a better choice for an algorithm. Without doing
comparative benchmarking personally, I decided to start with LZ4 compression and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;198&quot;&gt;add &lt;code&gt;zstd&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; once namespaced features are released in Rust&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some benchmarks have been updated to include compression for comparision. The
results are interesting to look at, but no serious comparisons should be drawn
yet. If you are under tight space constraints, this feature can save a lot of
storage space while not impacting performance in a major way.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;benchmarks&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;large-balanced&#x2F;4&#x2F;index.html#FindProduct&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&amp;#x2F;v0.2.0&amp;#x2F;benchmarks&amp;#x2F;commerce&amp;#x2F;large-balanced&amp;#x2F;4&amp;#x2F;FindProduct.png&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;lookup product by id&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see in this graph, the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;benchmarks&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Commerce
Benchmark&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; sometimes shows
improved performance over the uncompressed version. As always, performance will
depend on your hardware and operating environment, which is why this is an
opt-in feature.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The user who originally asked about this feature had reported that BonsaiDb&#x27;s
uncompressed database size a staggering 30x larger than the equivalent data in
Sled. The next day they were able to test a branch with the feature enabled. The
BonsaiDb database compressed with LZ4 shrunk to under half the size of their
Sled database.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Getting%20Started&quot; name=&quot;Getting%20Started&quot;&gt;
    Getting Started
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic setup instructions and a list of examples. We have started writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.2.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we have tried to write &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;good documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear from you if you have questions or feedback. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community Discourse forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also welcome anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;new&quot;&gt;open an issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with any questions or feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dream big with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we believe that it can simplify writing and deploying complex, data-driven applications in Rust. We would love &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;labels&#x2F;good%20first%20issue&quot;&gt;additional contributors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who have similar passions and ambitions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you build something with one of our libraries, we would love to hear about it. Nothing makes us happier than hearing people are building things with our crates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Announcing BonsaiDb 0.1.0: A Rust NoSQL database that grows with you</title>
		<published>2022-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-02-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/announcing-bonsaidb-alpha/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/announcing-bonsaidb-alpha/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is new database aiming to be the most developer-friendly Rust database. BonsaiDb has a unique feature set geared at solving many common data problems. We have a page dedicated to answering the question: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;What is BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#x27;s been over six months since &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;pliantdb-v0-1-0-dev-4-released-custom-apis-unique-views-webassembly&#x2F;69&quot;&gt;we announced PliantDb 0.1.0-dev.4&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Beyond the name change, a lot has changed. We&#x27;ve been focusing our efforts on stabilizing BonsaiDb&#x27;s core architecture so that we can start building applications with BonsaiDb. Today, we&#x27;re excited to announce our first alpha release: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.0&quot;&gt;version 0.1.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Upgrading%20existing%20databases&quot; name=&quot;Upgrading%20existing%20databases&quot;&gt;
    Upgrading existing databases
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no upgrade path from 0.1.0-dev.4. Prior to this release, we warned against using this project outside of experimentation, so we hope this is not an issue for anyone. However, if this is devastating news to anyone, please reach out to us, and we can try to help.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#What%20does%20alpha%20mean%3F&quot; name=&quot;What%20does%20alpha%20mean%3F&quot;&gt;
    What does alpha mean?
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest barrier to adoption was our own making: our README actively discouraged early-adopters except out of experimentation. We held off releasing this first alpha until after we were confident in the foundation we&#x27;ve laid. We expect bugs will be found, and we are certain that at least one user will lose data. It&#x27;s just a fact of life. The alpha phase enables adventurous users to begin using BonsaiDb to help us find these issues before we label BonsaiDb &amp;quot;stable.&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage users that attempt to use this in an environment where data loss would be detrimental to utilize and test the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;about&#x2F;#backup-restore&quot;&gt;backup and restore&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; functionality regularly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are still planning to add features during the alpha phase, but those features will focus on the higher-level database functionality. Changes to how data is stored will be minimal or non-existent unless bugs or performance issues are uncovered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#What%27s%20new%3F&quot; name=&quot;What%27s%20new%3F&quot;&gt;
    What&amp;#x27;s new?
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the fundamental ideas powering BonsaiDb are still the same as previous releases, this release left almost no code untouched. The GitHub stats show &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;compare&#x2F;v0.1.0-dev.4...v0.1.0&quot;&gt;29,933 additions and 11,678 across 450 commits&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; -- and those stats don&#x27;t include the new crates introduced. The &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&#x2F;tag&#x2F;v0.1.0&quot;&gt;release on GitHub&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; covers all of the changes, but we wanted to draw attention to a few notable entries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-3&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#New%20Storage%20Layer&quot; name=&quot;New%20Storage%20Layer&quot;&gt;
    New Storage Layer
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the hood, this alpha unveils a new storage engine: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. While the storage layer we were using before (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;sled.rs&quot;&gt;Sled&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) is incredibly fast, it also is quite complex and didn&#x27;t quite fit BonsaiDb&#x27;s needs perfectly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nebari maintains a fairly straightforward design while still achieving fairly competitive benchmarks for being such a new library. Additionally, its implementation can be custom-tailored to the workloads we need to support BonsaiDb. Nebari &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;nebari-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;performs quite well&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in our initial testing.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-4&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#New%20Serialization%20Ecosystem&quot; name=&quot;New%20Serialization%20Ecosystem&quot;&gt;
    New Serialization Ecosystem
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of our design from the beginning was to allow users to store arbitrary chunks of data as a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.1.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;document.html&quot;&gt;document&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In other words, users shouldn&#x27;t be forced into a specific serialization or encoding format for their data. Unfortunately, a side effect of this was the API&#x27;s usability suffered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This alpha addresses the API shortcomings with functionality designed around &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;transmog&quot;&gt;Transmog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Transmog is a fairly simple concept: a universal set of traits to describe a basic serialization and deserialization interface. An example of Transmog in cation can be found in our new example: &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;examples&#x2F;view-histogram&#x2F;examples&#x2F;view-histogram.rs&quot;&gt;view-histogram.rs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. It demonstrates storing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;hdrhistogram&#x2F;latest&#x2F;hdrhistogram&#x2F;struct.Histogram.html&quot;&gt;hdrhistogram::Histogram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a view&#x27;s value by implementing the needed Transmog traits, allowing these types of fluid queries:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#65737e;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F; Retrieve an `hdrhistogram::Histogram` with all samples recorded.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; total_histogram = db.view::&amp;lt;AsHistogram&amp;gt;().&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;reduce&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;().await?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;println!(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;99th Percentile overall: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt; (&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt; samples)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    total_histogram.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;value_at_quantile&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;0.99&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;),
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    total_histogram.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;len&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using Transmog as a foundation, BonsaiDb provides streamlined APIs for interacting with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;0.1.0&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;connection&#x2F;trait.Connection.html#using-connection-with-collectiondocumentt&quot;&gt;serialized collections&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-5&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Extensible%20TCP%20Handling&quot; name=&quot;Extensible%20TCP%20Handling&quot;&gt;
    Extensible TCP Handling
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a vision that BonsaiDb will be a complete application development platform, including building web applications. Therefore, we have created a way to theoretically use any HTTP framework and mount the BonsaiDb WebSockets at a specific route.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a new example (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;examples&#x2F;axum&#x2F;examples&#x2F;axum.rs&quot;&gt;axum.rs&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) which demonstrates how to accomplish this using the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;crates.io&#x2F;crates&#x2F;axum&quot;&gt;Axum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; framework.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-6&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#At-Rest%20Encryption&quot; name=&quot;At-Rest%20Encryption&quot;&gt;
    At-Rest Encryption
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not all hosting environments offer encrypted filesystems, and almost all applications store some Personally Identifiable Information (PII). Therefore, it is a good practice (and often a legal requirement) to ensure that all sensitive information is stored encrypted on the disk.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BonsaiDb now optionally supports transparent &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.1.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;administration&#x2F;encryption.html&quot;&gt;at-rest encryption using externally stored keys&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-7&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Improving%20the%20Ecosystem&quot; name=&quot;Improving%20the%20Ecosystem&quot;&gt;
    Improving the Ecosystem
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New and updated crates in the Rust ecosystem power this release:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-8&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#New%20Crates&quot; name=&quot;New%20Crates&quot;&gt;
    New Crates
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;ModProg&#x2F;derive-where&#x2F;&quot;&gt;derive-where&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Derive standard traits more easily when generic type bounds are involved&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Low-level, transactional key-value storage&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;ordered-varint&quot;&gt;ordered-varint&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Variable-length signed and unsigned integer encoding that retains sortable at the byte-level&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;pot&quot;&gt;Pot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: A concise, self-describing binary serialization format.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;rustme&quot;&gt;RustMe&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Tool and library for managing READMEs for Rust projects&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;transmog&quot;&gt;Transmog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Universal serialization traits and utilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-9&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Updated%20Crates&quot; name=&quot;Updated%20Crates&quot;&gt;
    Updated Crates
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are existing crates we&#x27;ve worked on as part of developing this release of BonsaiDb:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;User65k&#x2F;async-acme&#x2F;&quot;&gt;async-acme&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Async ACME client for the TLS-ALPN-01 challenge type&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;RustCrypto&#x2F;password-hashes&quot;&gt;password-hashes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Password hashing functions and KDFs.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;crates.io&#x2F;crates&#x2F;zeroize&quot;&gt;Zeroize&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: Utilities for zeroing buffers before deallocating.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-10&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#In-progress%20Crates&quot; name=&quot;In-progress%20Crates&quot;&gt;
    In-progress Crates
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We removed OPAQUE support for now, but will be reintroducing it &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;161&quot;&gt;in the
future&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;@daxpedda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has been hard at work helping bring the
ecosystem up to the current draft spec:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;custodian&quot;&gt;custodian-password&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: High-level implementation of the OPAQUE password-authenticated key exchange protocol.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;novifinancial&#x2F;opaque-ke&quot;&gt;opaque-ke&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: An implementation of the OPAQUE password-authenticated key exchange protocol. Used by custodian-password.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;novifinancial&#x2F;voprf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;voprf&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: An implementation of a verifiable oblivious pseudorandom function. Used by &lt;code&gt;opaque-ke&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-11&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Getting%20Started&quot; name=&quot;Getting%20Started&quot;&gt;
    Getting Started
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;new homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic setup instructions and a list of examples. We have started writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;v0.1.0&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we have tried to write &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.rs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;good documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would love to hear from you if you have questions or feedback. We have &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;community Discourse forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&quot;&gt;Discord server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but also welcome anyone to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;new&quot;&gt;open an issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; with any questions or feedback.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We dream big with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and we believe that it can simplify writing and deploying complex, data-driven applications in Rust. We would love &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;labels&#x2F;good%20first%20issue&quot;&gt;additional contributors&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who have similar passions and ambitions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, if you build something with one of our libraries, we would love to hear about it. Nothing makes us happier than hearing people are building things with our crates!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>BonsaiDb January update: Alpha Next Week</title>
		<published>2022-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/january-2022-update/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/january-2022-update/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a pure Rust database that grows with you. It already is &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;feature-rich&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but we are still working towards our initial alpha. This month&#x27;s update will highlight the changes since the last update and cover what&#x27;s remaining before our alpha release.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;highlighted-updates&quot;&gt;Highlighted updates&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have made &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;compare&#x2F;355c7904dd9b64874d99721941d2b0c0002f26b4...c1bc3ca6ce488fe8c26d265a3b1e9b8fb62d1347&quot;&gt;90 commits (+8,406&#x2F;-3,097)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; since &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;bonsaidb-december-update-finishing-up-alpha-1&#x2F;88&quot;&gt;last month&#x27;s update&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Many improvements have been made based on feedback from early adopters. Thank you to everyone who has asked a question, reported an issue, or provided any feedback!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Key-Value%20Store%20Optimization&quot; name=&quot;Key-Value%20Store%20Optimization&quot;&gt;
    Key-Value Store Optimization
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I firmly believe in under-promising and over-delivering. So when I was writing the &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;about&quot;&gt;about page&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; originally, I had to clarify in the &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;about&#x2F;#key-value&quot;&gt;Key-Value section&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that the performance was limited by &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;120&quot;&gt;the current design&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. As such, I decided I would prefer to go ahead and implement the design proposed in that issue.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Key-Value store is meant to perform atomic operations with reasonable durability. This is the primary difference between the goals of the Key-Value store and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;collection.html&quot;&gt;Collection&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; storage. The Key-Value store is meant to be a good alternative to running &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;redis.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Redis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and Redis uses a delayed persistence design.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve copied the general design of how persistence works, except that with BonsaiDb the database isn&#x27;t kept in memory constantly. This means that BonsaiDb&#x27;s Key-Value store can contain more data than the RAM on your machine, something that is possible but not recommended with Redis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By default, BonsaiDb will persist each operation after it&#x27;s performed. This can cause a lot of extra disk IO if thousands of operations are being performed per second. Additionally, it can cause file bloat due to the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;append-only file format&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; utilized. Instead, it&#x27;s recommended to &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;administration&#x2F;configuration.html#key-value-persistence&quot;&gt;configure persistence&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; such that writes are delayed based on what you feel is a good balance for your use case. For example:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span&gt;Storage::open(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    StorageConfiguration::new(&amp;amp;database_directory)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;key_value_persistence&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(KeyValuePersistence::lazy([
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            PersistenceThreshold::after_changes(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;1&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;and_duration&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Duration::from_secs(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;5&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)),
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            PersistenceThreshold::after_changes(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;10&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;),
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;  ])
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This configuration has two rules: persist after 5 seconds if there is at least 1 change, and perist if there are at least 200 changes. This means if BonsaiDb unexpectedly is killed, at most the most recent 5 seconds of changes would be lost. However, if a batch of changes is written, they will be persisted immediately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how does the key-value store perform compared to Redis?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;suite&#x2F;get-bytes&#x2F;1KiB&#x2F;report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&amp;#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&amp;#x2F;suite&amp;#x2F;get-bytes&amp;#x2F;1KiB&amp;#x2F;report&amp;#x2F;violin.svg&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;get-key 1kb&quot; style=&quot;background-color: #DDD&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well, as you might expect, if you don&#x27;t have network access, things go very fast -- measured in nanoseconds on my personal computer. However, the networking performance leaves something to be desired. After doing a lot of profiling, I could see that the TLS for the QUIC connection accounts for roughly 30% of the time spent. However, that still is a little slower than the WebSocket implementation, which in turn is significantly slower than Redis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My profiling has led me to believe that &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;129&quot;&gt;switching to Socketto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will bring the WebSocket implementation closer by reducing the number of allocations. Only time will tell if that will match Redis&#x27;s performance, but I&#x27;m hopeful it will be close enough to not care. For the QUIC connection, our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;other major contributor&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has plans to dig in and see what can be done to reduce some of the allocations we saw in the profiling we did.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Collection%20Benchmarks&quot; name=&quot;Collection%20Benchmarks&quot;&gt;
    Collection Benchmarks
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My last &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;commerce-benchmark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; goes into detail about a new benchmark I wrote to attempt to simulate a simple relational database workload. The results were staggering to me.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;bonsaidb.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;commerce-benchmark&#x2F;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&amp;#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&amp;#x2F;commerce&amp;#x2F;large-writeheavy&amp;#x2F;8&amp;#x2F;LookupProduct.png&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;find prodcut by id graph&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly every operation across every workload showed all ways of accessing BonsaiDb outperforming PostgreSQL significantly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Rethinking%20Serialization&quot; name=&quot;Rethinking%20Serialization&quot;&gt;
    Rethinking Serialization
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One problem that I had with BonsaiDb is that I didn&#x27;t want to force users into a specific serialization format. The base document type contains a buffer of bytes -- you can store whatever you&#x27;d like as a document. I believe our new serialization format, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;pot&quot;&gt;Pot&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, is a great choice, but there are very good reasons to make it easy to support any serialization format.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This month I spent time creating &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;transmog&quot;&gt;Transmog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, my take on an approach to universal serialization traits. This project aims at creating a common interface that most serialization formats could offer an implementation of. By leveraging transmog, BonsaiDb&#x27;s &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;docs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;core&#x2F;schema&#x2F;trait.SerializedCollection.html&quot;&gt;SerializedCollection&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; trait can be used to automatically serialize and deserialize your collection types for you regardless of the format you&#x27;re storing them as. Additionally, View value serialization is now powered by Transmog, as our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;blob&#x2F;main&#x2F;examples&#x2F;view-histogram&#x2F;examples&#x2F;view-histogram.rs&quot;&gt;hdrhistogram view example&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; demonstrates:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#65737e;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F;&#x2F; A view for [`Samples`] which produces a histogram.
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;#[&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;derive&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(Debug, Clone)]
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;pub struct &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AsHistogram;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;impl &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;View &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AsHistogram {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Collection = Samples;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Key = &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Value = SyncHistogram&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;name&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;) -&amp;gt; Name {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        Name::new(&amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;as-histogram&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;impl &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;SerializedView &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AsHistogram {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Format = &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;format&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() -&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self::&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Format {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;impl &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Format&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;&amp;#39;static&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, SyncHistogram&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AsHistogram {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;type &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Error = HistogramError;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;serialize_into&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;W: std::io::Write&amp;gt;(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;value&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: &amp;amp;SyncHistogram&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;mut &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;writer&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: W,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    ) -&amp;gt; Result&amp;lt;(), &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self::&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Error&amp;gt; {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        V2Serializer::new()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;serialize&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(value, &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;mut&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; writer)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;map_err&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(HistogramError::Serialization)?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        Ok(())
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;impl &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;OwnedDeserializer&amp;lt;SyncHistogram&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;for &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;AsHistogram {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;fn &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#8fa1b3;&quot;&gt;deserialize_from&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;lt;R: std::io::Read&amp;gt;(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;mut &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;reader&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;: R,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    ) -&amp;gt; Result&amp;lt;SyncHistogram&amp;lt;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u64&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;gt;, &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;Self::&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Error&amp;gt; {
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;        hdrhistogram::serialization::Deserializer::new()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;deserialize&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;mut&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; reader)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;map&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(SyncHistogram::from)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;            .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;map_err&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(HistogramError::Deserialization)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    }
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;}
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example shows how using &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;transmog&quot;&gt;Transmog&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; we&#x27;re able to use the custom serialization functions built into the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;crates.io&#x2F;crates&#x2F;hdrhistogram&quot;&gt;hdrhistogram&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; crate. Querying the view returns a &lt;code&gt;SyncHistogram&amp;lt;u64&amp;gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt; directly:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; total_histogram = db.view::&amp;lt;AsHistogram&amp;gt;().&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;reduce&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;().await?;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;println!(
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &amp;quot;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt;99th Percentile overall: &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt; (&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;{}&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#a3be8c;&quot;&gt; samples)&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;quot;,
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; total_histogram.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;value_at_quantile&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#d08770;&quot;&gt;0.99&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;),
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; total_histogram.&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;len&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;);
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this example shows the inredible power of our &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;view.html&quot;&gt;map&#x2F;reduce views&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the Rust type system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-3&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Alpha%20coming%20next%20week&quot; name=&quot;Alpha%20coming%20next%20week&quot;&gt;
    Alpha coming next week
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a chat this morning with our other major contributor, (&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;daxpedda&quot;&gt;@daxpedda&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), to try to understand the implications of the breaking changes coming in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;novifinancial&#x2F;opaque-ke&quot;&gt;OPAQUE-KE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; crate. The result of the conversation was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;158&quot;&gt;this issue to implement traditional password hashing&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The first alpha will not contain OPAQUE as we&#x27;re going to wait until an update supporting  draft-irtf-cfrg-opaque-07 is released. This is one of the things he&#x27;s been working hard on for months, and he&#x27;s near the point where we can integrate the changes into BonsaiDb!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as OPAQUE is still a draft specification, there is too much possibility that things will break again in the future before being stabilized. We will help support these upgrades, but it&#x27;s not going to be the best administration experience, and it will potentially require utilizing multiple crate versions in the long run.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I swap out this implementation, I&#x27;m going to be creating a 0.1 branch &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;in the repository&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We will be using the 0.x version range for our alpha and beta phases and eventually &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;137&quot;&gt;release 1.0&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as the first stable version.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will ask early adopters to check it out ahead of releasing to crates.io at the end of next week. I&#x27;ll send out a message on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;discord.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our Discord&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well as update &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;issues&#x2F;87&quot;&gt;this issue&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; once the branch is available.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, our &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;&quot;&gt;homepage&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has basic getting started information including a full list of examples. I look forward to hearing what people build with BonsaiDb!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have questions or comments? Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;bonsaidb-january-update-alpha-next-week&#x2F;93&quot;&gt;our forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Benchmarking relational data in BonsaiDb</title>
		<published>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://bonsaidb.io/blog/commerce-benchmark/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://bonsaidb.io/blog/commerce-benchmark/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you aren&#x27;t familiar with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, check out our &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;about&#x2F;&quot;&gt;What is
BonsaiDb?&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; page.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we&#x27;re working towards our first alpha, I&#x27;ve been trying to anticipate
questions potential users might have when looking at BonsaiDb for the first
time. Although we are keeping the alpha label, we are hoping to find some
adventurous users who are excited at our vision of a database designed for and
written in Rust.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One obvious question that almost everyone will ask at some point when hearing
about a new database: &lt;strong&gt;how does it perform?&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BonsaiDb is a unique database. It is best described as a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;NoSQL&quot;&gt;NoSQL&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
database, but traditionally NoSQL databases tend to favor eventual consistency
and speed over ACID compliance. When starting this project, I specifically
wanted to have all the guarantees PostgreSQL makes, but easier to use and deploy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until this past week, I knew from previous benchmarks that &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&quot;&gt;Nebari&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (our
underlying storage layer) was &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;nebari&#x2F;tree&#x2F;192b6d34c6ad1350c2e469359f51423f69b1e2d4&#x2F;benchmarks&quot;&gt;pretty fast&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, but I had no real
indicator of how BonsaiDb would perform relative to PostgreSQL.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Designing%20a%20Benchmark%20Suite&quot; name=&quot;Designing%20a%20Benchmark%20Suite&quot;&gt;
    Designing a Benchmark Suite
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had three different parameters I wanted to measure:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dataset size&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The amount of concurrent workers&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read-heavy vs Write-heavy workloads&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to create a benchmark suite inspired by the needs of an ecommerce
website. The basic idea is to generate an initial data set, a list of plans for
workers to execute, and test the dataset and plans using different quantities of
workers. The operations being benchmarked are:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lookup product by id&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Find product by name (exact match)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create shopping cart&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add product to cart&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Checkout&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review a product&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A single plan is generated by using probabilities to adjust how many plans
succeed in each step of the shopping process. Some plans will search for
products and never add them to a cart; Others will not only purchase the
product, but also write a review. By adjusting the probabilities of each action
occurring, we create a funnel that allows us to adjust the ratio of reads and
writes.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve written some more notes on the implementation of the benchmark itself, such
as how aggregation of ratings is handled, in the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;tree&#x2F;73aa1b1e8086c23bee10cd3024bf5fcaff8ea13e&#x2F;benchmarks&#x2F;benches&#x2F;commerce#user-content-benchmark-notes&quot;&gt;benchmark&#x27;s
README&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-1&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#BonsaiDb%20is%20faster%20than%20I%20had%20hoped%21&quot; name=&quot;BonsaiDb%20is%20faster%20than%20I%20had%20hoped%21&quot;&gt;
    BonsaiDb is faster than I had hoped!
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These graphs show the accumulated execution time of each operation:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;large-writeheavy&#x2F;8&#x2F;index.html#LookupProduct&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&amp;#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&amp;#x2F;commerce&amp;#x2F;large-writeheavy&amp;#x2F;8&amp;#x2F;LookupProduct.png&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;lookup product by id&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;large-writeheavy&#x2F;8&#x2F;index.html#FindProduct&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&amp;#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&amp;#x2F;commerce&amp;#x2F;large-writeheavy&amp;#x2F;8&amp;#x2F;FindProduct.png&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;find product by name&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;large-writeheavy&#x2F;8&#x2F;index.html#AddProductToCart&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https:&amp;#x2F;&amp;#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&amp;#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&amp;#x2F;commerce&amp;#x2F;large-writeheavy&amp;#x2F;8&amp;#x2F;AddProductToCart.png&quot; class=&quot;block-image&quot; alt=&quot;add product to cart&quot;   &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This set of graphs is from the &amp;quot;large, write-heavy, 2 workers per core&amp;quot;
benchmark, run on a &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;scaleway.com&quot;&gt;Scaleway&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; GP1-XS instance running
Ubuntu 20.04 with 4 CPU cores, 16GB of RAM, and local NVME storage. The entire
suite&#x27;s results can be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs-storage.s3.us-west-000.backblazeb2.com&#x2F;bonsaidb-scaleway-gp1-xs&#x2F;commerce&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;viewed here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as well.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I started seeing these results, I was simply blown away. I&#x27;ve tried to be &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;tree&#x2F;73aa1b1e8086c23bee10cd3024bf5fcaff8ea13e&#x2F;benchmarks&#x2F;benches&#x2F;commerce#user-content-benchmark-notes&quot;&gt;as
fair as possible&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in writing this benchmark suite. Over time I
plan on adding additional database backends for comparison, as well as
additional operations as BonsaiDb gains more features.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One major difference between PostgreSQL and BonsaiDb is the lack of SQL. With
BonsaiDb, the query language is Rust itself. This is why I often refer to
BonsaiDb as a &lt;em&gt;programmable database&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;. The interface for accessing your data is
how &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;about&#x2F;concepts&#x2F;view.html&quot;&gt;you design it&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. For example, here&#x27;s the implementation of find product:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;pre data-lang=&quot;rust&quot; style=&quot;background-color:#2b303b;color:#c0c5ce;&quot; class=&quot;language-rust &quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-rust&quot; data-lang=&quot;rust&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; product = Product::load(&amp;amp;operation.name, &amp;amp;&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.database)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .await
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;unwrap&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;() &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#65737e;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F; Result
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;unwrap&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(); &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#65737e;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F; Option&amp;lt;CollectionDocument&amp;lt;Product&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;let&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; rating = &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#bf616a;&quot;&gt;self
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .database
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .view::&amp;lt;ProductReviewsByProduct&amp;gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;with_key&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(product.id as &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#b48ead;&quot;&gt;u32&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;with_access_policy&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(AccessPolicy::NoUpdate)
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;reduce&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;()
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .await
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;    .&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#96b5b4;&quot;&gt;unwrap&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(); &lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color:#65737e;&quot;&gt;&#x2F;&#x2F; Returns a f32
&lt;&#x2F;span&gt;&lt;&#x2F;code&gt;&lt;&#x2F;pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;-2&quot;&gt;


&lt;a href=&quot;#Trying%20out%20BonsaiDb&quot; name=&quot;Trying%20out%20BonsaiDb&quot;&gt;
    Trying out BonsaiDb
    &lt;i class=&quot;bi bi-link-45deg hoverable&quot;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;i&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&quot;&gt;BonsaiDb&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is currently labeled experimental. We are working to stabilize
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;custodian&quot;&gt;custodian-password&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, which has involved updating many existing
crates to improve the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;novifinancial&#x2F;opaque-ke&quot;&gt;OPAQUE-KE&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
ecosystem in Rust. After that is done, we are going to label BonsaiDb as alpha.
It hasn&#x27;t been used by many people yet, so we expect that there will be bugs and
some of those bugs might even cause loss of data. That being said, we&#x27;ve been
using it ourselves with &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;khonsulabs.com&#x2F;&quot;&gt;KhonsuLabs.com&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; since early
November 2021 with no issues, in addition to a couple other small test projects.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We encourage most users to wait another week or two until we have the alpha on
Crates.io, but for those looking to play with something new, we&#x27;d love any
feedback from early users. We&#x27;ve already made countless improvements to the API,
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;docs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dev.bonsaidb.io&#x2F;release&#x2F;guide&#x2F;&quot;&gt;user&#x27;s guide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;tree&#x2F;73aa1b1e8086c23bee10cd3024bf5fcaff8ea13e&#x2F;examples&quot;&gt;examples&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as a result of questions from early adopters.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&#x27;re interested in BonsaiDb but want to wait until we&#x27;ve released a stable
version, we invite you to subscribe to &lt;a href=&quot;&#x2F;blog&#x2F;atom.xml&quot;&gt;this site&#x27;s feed&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or
watch the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;github.com&#x2F;khonsulabs&#x2F;bonsaidb&#x2F;releases&quot;&gt;repository&#x27;s releases section&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are looking forward to seeing what types of applications BonsaiDb will power someday!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have questions or comments? Discuss this post on &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;community.khonsulabs.com&#x2F;t&#x2F;benchmarking-relational-data-in-bonsaidb&#x2F;91&quot;&gt;our forums&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
